Look at the call to the order, the regular meeting of the Miami City Council for the day, the day, and time.
I didn't do this public income at unscheduled personal garages and only on it, it's pushed to address the council on any of the agenda items.
They're being non-ident.
Excuse me, that was okay.
I don't have three as a consent agenda, staff is recommending items four through nine for the consent agenda.
If you take a quick look at those, we have no questions.
Okay, the motion to approve.
Okay, that's the very vision of the order map.
Is that just based on the fact that we had access to it?
Correct. Okay.
We need to address the order maps to bring in the new prom case, but I have to say the city.
So there's no further discussion.
I'll make much to prove.
Second.
Will a prom, please?
Winston.
Aye.
Work it.
We will.
Aye.
I took those two item.
Order taken to Tim.
Item 10 is displayed.
Proposed items of circles and all draws items to be offered.
The public sale price to high.
All right.
Getting into your tools.
And so we have a lot of items that we've been proposed for circles.
We've got a lot of apartments.
We've kind of been collecting those things.
Or right now.
It'd be the goals.
It's a piece of infrastructure that are no longer even repairable.
So some of this.
We are asking to surplus to put in a online option.
Some of these things we want to surplus so that we can just take them on to the scrap
them for the value of the scrap.
And tell them, right.
And on the part is, we have two kinds of scrap.
We have things that are just obviously trash that just go off to the pile and we'll take
them on.
But then we have things that have, like, an identifying number of cereal
is maybe as most of it's coming from like wastewater treatment.
Where there's things like big valves, 24 inch valves that have no value.
It can't happen with air.
So we're asking the scrap stuff.
And do we, we don't do any sort of public option.
Have we had it in several years?
You don't plan on doing what?
We're not.
Randy did the last one.
They usually do those every two years.
But we're trying to use this gut deals opportunity for people to just a baby.
And on my option, like eBay, we do publicize it so that the local people learn
and the other ways to pay and get the word out to people can't participate.
because it's such a cost savings to us, because it's very expensive to do an oxygen
urion, paying all their people and handling money, much, much more valuable asset
as it goes to you.
So, this will be our first big test of a big amount.
So are we required to do the notices in the paper, and so we do the public notice whatever
is necessary.
I noticed there are several bicycles on here.
Now, are these bicycles that have been recovered that are presumed to be stolen?
They are the majority of them are now property, obviously most of them are junk, we have
them for quite some time, and it's been a long time ago, but I had a bicycle, and the
police department actually had a tag that they connected to there that would identify that
as being your property in case it was taken.
So, if I had a bicycle now, it was missing how would it have to be identified by some sort
of marking, or what we think about?
We've had some bicycles in our neighborhood that have been taken, and I don't know if it's just
an honor system that can come down, and you happen to have it in your inventory, or do
you have to have some sort of marking numbers.
I'll ever identify if it's a amount of property or not to real pick you on bikes, because we
have a massive bus, we've tried to bicycle registration the aid of that over the year,
we've been a couple of different things, and most of them were just found property that nobody
claims.
More often than not, it's stolen by, because you can be abandoned by whoever steals it, and
so we find them everywhere, all of them are bound.
10-its of my question.
And people have plenty of time that we can come to it.
I absolutely love being here.
Here's what we've had.
And we quite from so long, we have no place to go.
Is this the same side we could all of our kitchen stuff on?
Yes.
And we get pretty well.
The beautiful thing is that the people have to come and get it, and it's on them, because
we're lost to have to ship it.
So you just understand, you're still a sail, and you're right on it.
We're getting more questions.
Do we have a motion to provide intent to clearing the closed items of the surplus?
I will make that next.
Second.
We just tell you one more thing, and that's that the department is looking at this overall list.
And so I know the tractor that's on there is going to come off.
And that's okay.
We can remove it from the surplus and bring it back to our inventory that it's going to go to the park.
So just so you know there might be some days pulled from this list before we actually option them.
Right now we have it heading to the separate you first through the tent.
Okay.
Roller always.
Lewis.
Hi.
Western.
Forester.
Fork it.
I'm 11.
There's nomination of council member.
Remember to serve as mayor of protest and poor.
Brian, of course, has served as mayor of protest.
Up until.
Last month.
The way the charter is written is when you were terminal office in your.
Occupational occupying of that seat as mayor of protest.
Also automatically in.
So you.
So I have to nominate someone else.
I've asked Brian if he would be willing to serve in that capacity again.
And he is agreed to do so.
So I am offering him as my nomination.
Looks to prove.
Second.
We'll call please.
Western.
Ork it.
Lewis.
I don't vote.
And I don't.
Brian.
Or.
Can.
Oh, yeah.
Absolutely.
All right.
Thank you, Brian.
Thank you.
I'm.
Yes.
I don't.
I'm.
I'm too.
Besides I.
So.
I don't.
I'm.
Be.
Be D.
Me.
It's good to not.
Bess.
I'm grow.
I mean.
changes, or any forecast changes, so everything status quo.
Do you let me ask you, and I know the budget amendments
400 consent agenda was one of those budget amendments
include the amendment for the legal fees.
Yes. So we've already approved that.
We've already approved that. We've already approved that.
We just approved that as the budget amendment. This means not correct.
And so in this budget contemplates that.
It does not only contemplates that approval, but it also
modifies the payment back to the rainy day funded extent.
it by about another 18 months because we fully intend to have that money go back into the rainy day fund.
Does anybody have any additional questions that they want to ask about the budget?
I think staff would have a pretty thorough job of giving us the big overview and we've had the information for a couple of weeks now to look at it in the most specifically for any questions.
I think he was brought up the last time we had this about maybe a presentation from Mades to see what our money is funding there.
I'd be willing to listen to that again.
I don't know when that could be set up.
And I talked to Steve on Monday and told him that we want him to do that sometime this month and he said, just let him know when.
And also spoke with Dean actually just before this meeting.
We don't actually fund that until July one.
I mean, we would be approving it in this budget.
But we wouldn't be riding checks until July one, which would be after.
And as a reminder, that money is in the budget and then it's their choice if they ask for it then it's.
It's voted on to be released as that correct.
Well, Mades is no longer what I'm going to consider an outside organization because they don't.
You guys have a whole separate contract for them.
And the outside works have a specific contract.
Okay.
It's really kind of template.
I mean, you say contract for all those organizations and Mades is no longer in that group.
So you guys have a separate contract that you'd probably need to put it.
I think that's basically is not an automatic payment.
We are July one.
We do not automatically run a check.
So if we want to have that presentation before that's done, we certainly could pull off on that.
Okay.
Now, we do have on top of that, though, we do have a stipend for them for their utilities as well.
A 16,000, which this year it actually covered all of their utilities.
I think they came in at about, but we have one more month left.
We're probably coming in at about $14,000.
So we're probably saved about that.
So anyway, it's not, we don't consider them automatic.
And I know that you want to be talking to Steve about that.
That's not the process.
So I think our thought is, let's try to get that done before July one.
I remember currently, last year, I was split.
And they needed the money up.
I mean, I thought it was really quick.
I think it was.
I think it was $25,000.
It's like $25.
Yeah, right.
That's right.
I think that's right.
I was right in and there.
There was some cash.
There was some cash flow.
There was some relationship.
The utilities.
Yeah.
We're not in that situation.
No.
No, we're not.
And I didn't schedule a bang with him.
He asked, he said, I'll do it this month.
You just tell me, when.
And so, growing, I just needed to know something else.
I would like to.
Just point out very quickly at that meeting we talked about our study session this month in our last schedule meeting this month
Is the day after Memorial day and I got the distinct impression for everybody that you did not want to meet the day after Memorial day
So we could we could have Steve on our next agenda on June 4th if you'd like
It's good for ring. Yeah, that's good. I will not be your tune for it. Yeah, I'm the desk. I'm okay with that. I can go talk to him
Okay, they said we'll tell you we plan all that
Any other questions on anything so then we're looking for approval in jail
That will be the June 4th meeting as well
Okay, I'm 13 is other new business and you business anyone
14 staff reports and your packet
Stacks available for any question. I mean
Mayor and household radio announcements. How Dean's gonna power the fire start. So I don't have any things and may I also have anything
16 city manager communication. Well, obviously the current flooding is the thing that's taken a lot of our time the last couple of days
You know, and I'm getting into the details the first thing I want to do is just thank all of our staff
There are a lot of people here that we're here till three or four in the morning. Thank goodness
We did not have any tornatic activities or anything on that line
So it's just really been flooding and water that we've been experiencing right now. Most of the flooding that we've experienced is called flashletting
Space clear results of heavy rains. We've had over six inches of rain over the last 24 hour period
It's in a day to our roads. We had a number of them that we've had to close off
I don't know why people think that it's okay to drive around Barricade, but they don't and some people might find out that they're gonna get a ticket
We've had too many swift water rescues right now
We already have some structures in
Water because of this, but the good news is that originally and we have been putting on social media with the media as much as possible
We had an estimate that the
crest of this was going to be at 1 a.m. on Thursday at
About 26.8. I believe I don't know if I forget whether with the point was but it would have been one of the
Third highest
Recorded floods for the Niocial River
51 and 07 being the only two that were higher than this
We have been
Working on the adaptive storm management program. We had our first call this morning
The mayor was very much
on that, we made it very clear that we were concerned about the releases and they had increased
the releases at Pensacola down from about the spring, about 45,000 cubic feet per second,
to what they announced were going to be by 4,95,000 cubic feet per second and actually right
now they're talking about the discharges from Pensacola are over 100,000 cubic feet per second.
So that's a pretty robust relief that our release that's taking place right now.
It really, they look at the flood pools so we really aren't sure how long that release
is going to take place, but they're trying to keep that flood pool going.
That and a combination of the fact that the rain in the basin was not as high as what
the National Weather Service anticipated, that they're currently looking at the crest being
Thursday afternoon at about 23.8, so it's significantly less than it will still be flooding.
I don't think anybody should think that we're out in the clear yet, there's still
be rows that will be covered, there may be some buildings that will be in the water, but not as bad
as what we were originally anticipating, we're very happy about that.
We're keeping our EOC or emergency operations center, basically staffed and open as we are.
The next few days are still our potentials for a storm to come through, probably not as happy
as what we just had, but yet more water in a very saturated basin that we're having to deal with
at this point.
So I'll tell you, I think we're wrapping up this day feeling pretty good, there's still a lot
of work that's going to have to be done, there's still some people are going to have some flood
losses, but not nearly as bad as we anticipated, and we also feel that our messaging about
the issues that we have related to Grand Lake, related to the Grand Lake populations, related
to the real licensing of Grand Lake, the expenses that we were just, I was just asked about
in a relationship to the budget, that potentially was paying off, but we have to keep at it very
much.
I've said it many times, this is something that hurts my Emma, and there are solutions that people
would understand what those solutions would be.
So that's where we're at at this point.
We've got contractors down here from Texas, they're at the Conno-Lodge, and that was here
that called, and he just texted me and said they're telling 48 hours to get out of the motel,
so they're expecting to be flooded.
And we do, that's even at 23, we think there could be, there'll be water over Steve Holmes, that's
correct.
87 by mother actually worked there at one of the Conno-Lodge, and I remember there was water
almost up to the railroad tracks, so you're predicting it.
We're still predicting that, we've made contacts with property owners, we're trying to...
can continue to work with them. So, but it might be a situation of maybe a foot of water instead of
five feet of water. I believe the swimming pool got hit too. We also pumped out there and
our municipal pool. Yes, I was going to mention that. The big pool we have removed the
pumps and taken those out. It's right at the fringe and probably it will get into the pool.
We don't anticipate it being open more of that. Fortunately.
It's a very dangerous sandbag room. I don't know if we didn't have enough sandbags that's
a million gallon reservoir. I just hate to have three inches to make the difference. I mean maybe
two feet. It's right at the cusp right now. I mean, I didn't get a chance to go out and I drove by,
but it's right at the edge. I don't want to add anything on the pool.
The water doesn't come over the sides. It comes up to the drags.
So, that's what we get a lot of water. It feels like it will. We stripped it. We put the out and everything.
Everything. Everything is out. So, we will prepare it for a pot of water. That's the thing about how the
thing is about it. So, if 86 was the benchmark we were telling people that should go by at 266
is 93 of the intervention water. There's some information that we can give out at 90 meters. We'll try to
work on that because we just got the information about it. Just a few minutes before this meeting. So that's
fairly new to us. We really haven't put it down. I do think the idea of how we put photos of the 86
would had some very good responses on that because we could show these interactive maps all day long,
but it just helps to visualize and see what buildings were actually in the water in 86.
It was 80 meters. 93. Yeah, 93. We were at 24.09 and that's projected. 23.4 inches to be very similar.
Close to 93. Close to 9.4 inches. Probably don't have a nice convenient booklet from the 93 foot,
but we might have some. Very might have some. Anyway, I think it's helpful to give people
something other than just a number of this kind of an enduous. And a lot of people have this interactive
map that we've put out there, but a lot of people don't know how to interact with it. And I understand a lot
probably has a trouble with it. Meaning anything in the other city manager comment? No, I think that's it.
I was 17. This video would be continued to count on the telltale chambers.
We can be in meeting room 1 for the purposes of executive session.
Where did we go?
That's 4.
I'm in that pod you've been.
I know, okay, I'll see you over there.